Guide to the LeRoy Scott Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
LeRoy Scott papers
1921-1997
1970-1990
GEN MSS 993
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
15.71
(18 boxes)
Scott, LeRoy, 1917-2009
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Bolerium Books on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2011.
May 2011 Acquisition: gift of Bolerium Books.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
LeRoy Scott
LeRoy Scott (1917-2009) was a gay rights activist and cross dressing performer who used the drag name "Madame X."
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, journal, photographs, printed material and other papers by or relating to LeRoy Scott. Includes papers relating to the Corduroy Club and the Mattachine Society.
Arrangement
Organized into three groupings: March 2011 Acquisition; April 2011 Acquisition; and May 2011 Acquisition.
Scott, LeRoy, 1917-2009
- March 2011 Acquisition
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Purchased from Bolerium Books on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2011.
  - Corduroy Club papers, 1970-1972; 3 (Box 1)
  - Photographs
    - Sacramento, Cruise around Alcatras - [illegible], 1990 (Box 1)
    - Gene's Welcome Summer Cocktail, Harbortown, 1971 April 7 (Box 1)
    - BWMT - Wine + Cheese? Regional Conference, year?, [?] October 25 (Box 1)
    - [illegible] supper/Simon, Jerry, me, Hotel, Lee Brewster, NYC, 1991 February (Box 1)
    - [illegible] - airport, plane, 1st Day?, [?] July 19 (Box 1)
    - Christmas Party, Lloyd/Bab, Walter ?, 1988 January 7 (Box 1)
    - St. Patrick's Potluck, Bruce, BWMT, Pat's, Fish Bone..., 1990 April 24 (Box 1)
    - Gene's Fun + Games, BWMT at [Pogius?], 1988 Febraary 10 (Box 1)
    - Eagle Diner from WS - Montrase, 1988 April 21 (Box 1)
    - MS Potluck, Thanksgiving - Chicago, Gene, [?] November 30 (Box 1)
    - Unlabeled negatives, undated (Box 1)
    - Amtrack club car wine + cheese, Gene..., [?] April 26 (Box 1)
    - Photographs, 1976 March 31 (Box 1)
    - Unlabeled development envelope (Box 1)
    - Talent Show - SF 10 Convention, [?] July 19 (Box 1)
    - Photographs, 1973 February 23 (Box 1)
    - Unlabeled (Box 1)
    - Thanksgiving, [US Xmas?]/Boston Bar Party, 1990 December 14 (Box 1)
    - Unlabeled negatives, undated (Box 1)
    - Unlabeled, undated (Box 1)
    - Unlabeled, undated (Box 1)
    - "Photo Stat Orders", undated (Box 1)
  - Papers related to Church
    - Papers related to Church, 1960s-1970s; 3 (Box 1)
  - Playbills
    - Playbills, 1970s-1980s (Box 1)
      Scope and Contents
      Folder 1 of 9
    - Playbills, 1970s-1980s; 8 (Box 2)
      Folders 2-9 of 9
  - Correspondence
    - Correspondence, 1960s-1990s; 8 (Box 2)
      Folders 1-8 of 19
    - Correspondence, 1960s-1990s; 11 (Box 3)
      Folders 9-19 of 19
  - Personal papers
    - 3 notebooks, undated (Box 3)
    - Guest book, 1963 (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1960s-1980s; 2 (Box 3)
      Folders 1-2 of 7
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1960s-1980s; 5 (Box 4)
      Folders 3-7 of 7
    - "Misc. junk", 1970s; 2 (Box 4)
    - Album of postcards, undated (Box 4)
  - Gay Theatre papers
    - Programs, 1960s-1980s (Box 4)
    - Manhattan Lambda, undated (Box 4)
    - Programs, fliers, undated; 5 (Box 4)
  - Gay organization papers, undated; 2 (Box 4)
  - Printed materials
    - Kauri, 1965 August (Box 5)
    - Newsletters, 1960s-1970s; 2 (Box 5)
    - Magazines, 1974; 1990; 1992 (Box 5)
    - Newspapers, 1970s-1980s; 5 (Box 5)
    - Various printed materials, 1973-1977 (Box 5)
    - Drag Queens magazine, 1970s (Box 5)
    - BWMT -Cleavland, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Mattachine Papers, 1960s (Box 5)
- April 2011 Acquisition
  - Correspondence
    - Correspondence, 1920s-1980s; 14 (Box 6)
      Folders 1-14 of 17
    - Correspondence, 1920s-1980s; 3 (Box 7)
      Folders 15-17 of 17
    - Correspondence, 1930s-1960s (Box 7)
    - Correspondence, 1990s; 3 (Box 7)
    - Correspondence - Pieper, Simon, 1950s-1970s (Box 7)
    - Correspondence - "Personal Letter/Bill File", circa 1942 (Box 7)
    - Correspondence - postcards, 1930s-1960s (Box 7)
    - Correspondence - YMCA, 1939 (Box 7)
  - Printed materials
    - A Boyscout's Courage - Griggs, 1921 (Box 7)
    - Cincinnati Conservatory of Music - Annual Announcement, 1934-1936 (Box 7)
    - Conservatory Annuals - various, 1934-1944 (Box 7)
    - Detroit Conservatory of Music - Prospectus, 1933-1936 (Box 7)
    - Drag magazine - 5 issues, 1972-1978 (Box 7)
    - Gay Chicago Magazine - 5 issues, 1986-1992; 2 (Box 7)
    - In Step magazine - 3 issues, 1986-1989 (Box 7)
    - The Mirror - 3 issues, 1986 August (Box 7)
    - The Naked Civil Servant - Crisp, 1968 (Box 8)
    - Newsletters and periodicals - misc., 1920s-1980s; 4 (Box 8)
    - Newspapers - various, 1930s-1980s; 5 (Box 8)
    - Second Baptist Advocate - 2 issues, 1978-1979 (Box 8)
    - Songbooks, circa 1917-1940; 2 (Box 8)
    - The Technician - 6 issues, 1934-1936 (Box 8)
    - St. Cyprians Episcopal Church - 2 Bulletins, 1938 (Box 8)
    - The Young People's Journal - 8 issues, 1933-1936; 2 (Box 8)
  - Photographs, Art, and Realia
    - Photographs - "BWMT Convention 91, John K's Reception", 1991 June 23 (Box 9)
    - Photographs - "Gene Deck's Retirement", 1995 November 5 (Box 9)
    - Photographs - "Cleveland Convention '96, Back Stage, Hotel Bar", 1996 July 30 (Box 9)
    - Photographs - "New York Visit, Waldorf?", circa 1995 (Box 9)
    - Photographs, misc. and envelope, circa 1999 (Box 9)
    - Photographs - "NYC - Waldorf" (Box 9)
    - Photographs - "David's Daughter's Wedding" (Box 9)
    - Photographs - "Convention?" (Box 9)
    - Photographs - "Helen's Wedding", 1995 (Box 9)
    - Photographs - unlabeled (Box 9)
    - Photographs - "BWMT Convention '91, Talent Show II", 1991 July 7 (Box 9)
    - Photographs - "Last of Convention", 1991 July 20 (Box 9)
    - Photographs - "Cleveland", 1984 (Box 9)
    - Photographs - "BWMT Convention Key [?] Allfounder [?] House - Walk the Walk", 1995 July 27 (Box 9)
    - Photographs - "Hoaterville [?], Bill's Funeral Mass", 1995 July 3 (Box 9)
    - Easter booklet and datebook, 1967 (Box 9)
    - Photographs - "Living Room" (Box 9)
    - Photographs - "BWMT Convention 91 - Last Night Banquet", 1991 June 31 (Box 9)
    - Photographs - "BWMT Convention, Key West Airport, Last Brunch, [?] Scenes, Banquet, [?] Festival", 1995 July 27 (Box 9)
    - Photographs - "Mich Gene, Taste Festival", undated (Box 9)
    - Photographs - "Halloween, out & about, Gene's", 1994 November 9 (Box 9)
    - Photographs - "Bob's Birthday, Kevin's Birthday", 1994 May 9 (Box 9)
    - Photographs - "Bob's Mother's Birthday", undated (Box 9)
    - Photographs - "Michal State Fair, Gene Plaza, [?] sign cleaning", undated (Box 9)
    - Photographs - unlabeled, undated (Box 9)
    - Photographs - "Cafagna [?] Birthday Dunner", 1994 October 24 (Box 9)
    - Negatives, musical instrument rental card, empty envelope, undated; 1969; 1936; 1994 July 31 (Box 9)
    - Photographs - "Gene's Brunch", 1996 May 31 (Box 9)
    - Photographs - "Anniversary BWMT, W Al's", 1995 (Box 9)
    - Photographs - unlabeled, 1964 January (Box 10)
    - Photographs - "Christmas at Walt's", 1995 (Box 10)
    - Photographs - "Don's House, Hotel" - incl. note from George, undated (Box 10)
    - Photographs - from Ray Ottley, 1994 (Box 10)
    - Photographs - "Gene's Retirement, Announcement, Jim [?]" (Box 10)
    - Photographs - Genes 1996 Brunch", 1996 May 28 (Box 10)
    - Negatives, empty folder, various photographs, Y.M.C.A. Forum bulletin (Box 10)
    - Photographs - various, undated (Box 10)
    - Photographs - "Leather Show Washington, Richard's [?]", [?] January 31 (Box 10)
    - Photgraphs - "Bar Guild [?], Gene, St. Patrick's Games Night Glenn, Bill", 1996 April 15 (Box 10)
    - Photographs - "1995 Anniversary" (Box 10)
    - Photographs - "St. Patrick's Day", 1995 April 3 (Box 10)
    - Photographs - "Wall House, Broadway" (Box 10)
    - Photographs - untitled, 1964 January 22 (Box 10)
    - Photographs - "Jim's Brother, Christmas, Gene's Christmas Brunch" (Box 10)
    - Photographs - "Foleds [?] Fund Raiser" (Box 10)
    - Photographs - "Convention, Washington?, Key West?" (Box 10)
    - Photographs - "Drama Festival, My Birthday", 1992 June 2 (Box 10)
    - Photographs - "Betty Doars [?] Eyes and What Nats [?]?", 1991 May 7 (Box 10)
    - Photographs - "voided" (Box 10)
    - Photographs - "BWMT [?], My Award", 1994 (Box 10)
    - Photographs - "Intermezo" (Box 10)
    - Photographs - "Dinner June, Opera House Benefit, Train?" (Box 10)
    - Photographs - "Father's Day Deals, Hospital House", 1997 July 1 (Box 10)
    - Photographs - "Chicago Convention Balcony", 1995 July (Box 10)
    - Photographs - "Boat Ride, Jim C", 1996 August 25 (Box 10)
    - Photographs - "Mother's Woman of Year", 1975 June 10 (Box 10)
    - Negatives - "Washington Convention, Ns [?] Talent Show and Etc." (Box 10)
    - Negatives - "1 set to Mother", 1975 August 15 (Box 10)
    - Photographs - "Jim's Baptism", 1994 February 20 (Box 10)
    - Photographs - unlabeled, 1970s (Box 10)
    - Photographs - unlabeled, 1968 April (Box 10)
    - Photographs - unlabeled, 1965-1967 (Box 10)
    - Photographs - unlableled, 1956 October (Box 10)
    - Photographs - unlabeled misc. (Box 10)
    - Negatives - unlabeled misc. (Box 10)
    - Photographs - unlabeled, 4 (Box 11)
    - Empty photo envelopes, 1994-1996 (Box 11)
    - Negatives - "Old + New Mixed", 1997 September (Box 11)
    - Photo wheel - unlabeled (Box 11)
    - Photographs - "Bob's Birthday, Kevin's Birthday", 1994 May 9 (Box 11)
    - Photographs - "Potluck Scott's Birthday", 1990 October 29 (Box 11)
    - Photographs - "BWMT Convention 91 Banquet Detroit?", 1991 June 31 (Box 11)
    - Photographs - "BWMT Convention 91 Talent Show I", 1991 July 6 (Box 11)
    - Photographs - "BWMT Convention 91, Canada & Banquet?", 1991 June 31 (Box 11)
    - Photographs - "John Adams Lot next door" (Box 11)
    - Photographs - "BWMT 91 Convention, Als' Party", 1991 June 25 (Box 11)
    - Photographs - "BWMT Receoption at Regis", 1991 June 25 (Box 11)
    - Photographs - "NY Cocktail Party, Jim's Retirement, My Reunion, Last Day Plane", 1995 November 3 (Box 11)
    - Photographs - "John R's Reception, BWMT", 1991 June (Box 11)
    - Photographs - "BWMT Convention Sf Regis, Opening Reception, 1991 June (Box 11)
    - Photographs - unlabeled, 4 (Box 11)
    - Photocopied pages of photo albums, 1994 (Box 11)
    - Collages & Photocopies of Photo (Box 11)
    - Negatives - unlabeled, 1940s (Box 11)
    - Photographs - unlabeled - misc, 1950s (Box 11)
    - Photographs - unlabeled misc., 1960s (Box 11)
    - Photographs - unlabeled misc., 1970s-1990s (Box 11)
    - Photographs - unlabeled framed, circa1940s (Box 11)
    - Negatives - unlabeled misc. (Box 11)
    - Misc. correspondence (Box 11)
    - Detroit School of Music envelope, shooting gallery target (paper), 1959 January (Box 11)
    - Certificate in Recognition of Service by Ray Scott, 1963 August 6 (Box 11)
  - Ephemera, Programs and Organizational Papers
    - Stanislavski: the image of a man - flyer, 1965 (Box 12)
    - Petition to FDR for grand jury on Detroit attacks (blank) (Box 12)
    - West Side Gay Theater - Program, 1972 (Box 12)
    - Prince Hall Grand Chapter, Order of the Eastern Star, Michican, 1970s (Box 12)
    - Daughters of Isis, 1950s (Box 12)
    - Concert programs, 1943 (Box 12)
    - Misc. Printed Material (Box 12)
    - "The Union Jack Built" - Socialist Labor Party ad, 1940s-1950s (Box 12)
    - Playbills and Scripts (Box 12)
    - Playbills, 1970s-1990s (Box 12)
    - "Art literature, books, dramatics", 1940s (Box 12)
    - School papers, 1930s-1940s (Box 12)
    - Corduroy Club and Other Gay Organizations, 1960s-1980s; 2 (Box 12)
    - Music, performances, conservatories and entertainments, 1915-1970s (Box 12)
    - Papers relating to politics and public programs, 1940s (Box 12)
    - Miluakee, Wisconsin, 1980s (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous Printed and Personal Material (Box 12)
    - BWMT Papers and Clippings, 1980s-1990s (Box 12)
    - Detroit Ordinance District - circulars, 1945 (Box 12)
    - BWMT and other organizations, 1980-1990s (Box 12)
    - Church-related papers, 1930s-1970s (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous personal papers and printed material, 1930s-1990s (Box 12)
    - Music, performances, entertainment, 1940-1990s (Box 12)
  - Schoolwork, Writings and Personal Papers
    - The History of the United States - textbook, 1935 (Box 13)
    - Problems in American Life - textbook, 1935 (Box 13)
    - Shorthand Manual Simplified - textbook, 1955 (Box 13)
    - The Power of Concentration - textbook, 1930s (Box 13)
    - Schoolwork, 1935 (Box 13)
    - English notebooks, 1935 (Box 13)
    - Schoolwork, 1930s (Box 13)
    - Composition notebooks - City College, 1949 (Box 13)
    - Composition notebook, 1956 (Box 13)
    - School workbooks, 1930s-1940s (Box 13)
    - The Rational Method in Reading - textbook, 1920s? (Box 13)
    - Schoolwork, 1930s-1940s (Box 13)
    - Students' Counterpoint - textbook, 1940s? (Box 13)
    - Composition books, 1940; 2 (Box 14)
    - Stenography notebooks, 1937 (Box 14)
    - Address books, signature book, receipt books (Box 14)
    - Schoolwork (Box 14)
    - Music work, 1930 (Box 14)
    - Artwork, 1930s (Box 14)
    - Writings - "Dolly" and "A Senior in a Gay Environment" (Box 14)
    - Schoolwork, 1940s (Box 14)
    - Daily planner, 1997 (Box 14)
    - Stenography book, typewriting workbook (Box 14)
    - Clippings (photocopied), 1980s (Box 14)
    - Notebook (Box 14)
    - Miscellaneous, 1930s-1940s (Box 14)
    - Graduation cap (Box 15)
    - Infant Christening gown (Box 15)
    - Wood plaque - signed Leroy Scott Wingert School (Box 15)
    - Portrait on canvas, 1931 July 21 (Box 15)
    - Earthenware biscuit fired self portrait bust (Box 16)
    - Jewelry/Sequins (Box 16)
    - Decorative miniature parasol (Box 16)
  - Mattachine Society Papers
    - Mattachine Society - study questionnaire (Box 14)
- May 2011 Acquisition
  Gift of Bolerium Books.
  - Correspondence, 1944-1977 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence from Beta O. Scott, 1950-1977 (Box 17)
  - In Step vol. 3, iss. 3 (1986) and Stagebill Detroit (1983) (Box 17)
  - Photographs (Box 17)
  - Ephemera and programs, 1960s-1970s (Box 17)
  - MOHR Michigan Organization for Human Rights - Michigan Gay/Lesbian Freedom Parade/Festival, 1987 (Box 17)
  - Corduroy Club papers, 1968-1980 (Box 17)
  - Daily Journal - "Wayne State University Journalism", 1993 September (Box 17)
  - Personal papers, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 17)
  - Framed portrait [Beta O. Scott] (Box 17)
  - Sheet music, 1920s (Box 18)